# SHANAKA RUSITH

SENIOR SOFTWARE ENGINEER

#### **DETAILS**

#### **ADDRESS**

Berlin, 13347 Germany

#### PHONE

+4915213994016

#### **EMAIL**

rusith@mail.com

#### DATE OF BIRTH

December 23, 1996

#### LINKS

rusith.me

github.com/rusith

<u>LinkedIn</u>

**StackOverflow** 

#### GOOD AT

C#

JavaScript

SQL

React

NodeJS

.Net

MongoDB

### LANGUAGES

English

 $\bullet$   $\bullet$   $\bullet$   $\circ$ 

Sinhala; Sinhalese

• • • • •

#### HOBBIES

#### **PROFILE**

I am a technology-agnostic Software Engineer with over 6 years of experience. A self-taught programmer who started learning to program at the age of 16. Since then, I have spent my time learning and practicing new technologies and programming languages. I have worked with a large array of web technologies both back-end and front-end. My experience spans the full gamut of software engineering including web and other technologies which makes me a valuable asset to any software development company or startup looking for someone who can get in and do anything!

#### **EMPLOYMENT HISTORY**

### Senior Software Engineer, arive GmbH

Berlin

Oct 2021

Helped design, develop and maintain the ARIVE application, a quick commerce app based in Germany and France.

- Worked with Stripe and PayPal for the payment integration and was responsible for developing and maintaining the payment processing system.
- Worked on every part of the application including inventory management system, order processing, and payments.

### **Senior Software Engineer, Calcey Technologies**

Colombo

Jan 2021 — Sep 2021

Mostly worked on the <u>Nelly</u> project as a Senior Software Engineer. Technologies used were .Net and JavaScript (AngularJS). Mostly involved in background services such as sitemap generation, product activation.

## **Software Engineer, Calcey Technologies**

Colombo

Aug 2018 — Jan 2021

Design, Develop, Test large-scale production applications such as Nelly.com (fashion retailer). Calcey provides extended teams for companies. I was a member of the Nelly team for most of the time as a Software Engineer. Technologies used were .Net MVC and JavaScript.

And I worked on other projects as well in this period including big-data applications and Business Intelligence applications.

Technologies include PoweBl, Talend, Cassandra, Presto, Athena, PostgreSQL

### **Software Engineer, Bourke Technologies**

Colombo

Jul 2016 — Aug 2018

Roles were to design, develop software for enterprise applications, The main technologies used were .Net, SQL Server, and JavaScript. Gained a lot of exposure to other technologies as well such as mobile development.

I am an avid reader https//goodreads.com/rusith

Blogging https://rusith.me https://rusith.blogspot.com

Movies
I am a movie watcher as
well

### **Trainee Software Engineer, Bourke Technologies**

Feb 2016 — Jul 2016

During the training period, I learned the basics of software engineering and a lot of technologies and programming languages. Used .Net and JavaScript for most of the projects.

Colombo

Projects covered the apparel industry and service desk software.

#### OTHER PROJECTS

#### Pretzel.space

<u>Pretzel</u> (<u>App</u>) is a workspace app with integrated AI and a lot of other tools and capabilities such as task management, document editing, a document cloud.

Designed the codebase from the ground up. then continued the project with help of other developers. This project is in active development.

I could architect this complex project and maintain a clean, productive code base.

I handle the releases for Pretzel. I manage all release pipelines and the cloud architecture on AWS.

Technologies used: NodeJS, React, Apollo, Express, NextJS, MySQL. Most of the components are built using TypeScript

### ShopShare.tv

<u>ShopShare</u> is a video shopping platform built to help shopping easier by providing help from shopping and fashion experts. I helped to build the project from the ground up. and created the initial, complete version of the Chrome extension which the stylists use to record videos. And built the backend and some core UI components such as the Shopcast file management page.

For this project we used NodeJS, React, GraphQL, MySQL, I got the opportunity to work with AWS in this project. I handled the releases and created the release pipeline for this project while I was working with ShopShare.

### Soaksun

Soaksun is a website for a travel agency that offers packages to Sri Lanka.

Built from the ground up using NextJS with TypeScript.

### **BetterView**

BetterView was software made to make head-hunting easy. It will help you with the shortlisting process and will help to verify the candidate information.

Technologies used: Node (CoffeeScript), AngularJS (CoffeeScript), MongoDB

#### **OPEN-SOURCE PROJECTS**

#### Genius

<u>Genius</u> is a cross-platform clipboard manager created using the QT library. This was a great learning experience to learn C++. I still use it and it has been very useful for so many people.

### Genie

<u>Genie</u> was a big project for me. This is basically a code generation tool that can generate a complete data access layer for .Net projects. The aim was to support all major database systems. Technologies: .Net Core

#### Gimbli

<u>Gimbli</u> is a command-line utility that can generate multiple files using a single template file.

The project was completely test-driven. The coverage is still 100%. This tool has been useful to me to reduce boilerplate when creating, for example, React components.

### **GSSubtitle**

<u>GS Tag Editor</u> This is a desktop application I created to edit media tags on my media files. Used Windows Presentation Foundation to create the UI.

## **URD (UndoRedo)**

<u>URD</u> was my first-ever open-source project.

This is a helper to implement undo-redo actions in .Net applications.

#### **EDUCATION**

### **Secondary Education, St Thomas College**

Matale

Jan 2007 — Dec 2015

Secondary Education until A/Ls

## PGD (UG), BCS, the Charted Institute of IT

Colombo

Jan 2016

Started the BCS PGD (Higher Education Qualification) in 2016. But lost focus after completing the certificate level of the program. I had acquired my knowledge and abilities by myself so far throughout my career. That is the reason for losing focus on this program. I am hoping to complete this within the next two years.

### REFERENCES

## References available upon request